What happens behind these walls will change everything.
Conclave is a drama, thriller film directed by Edward Berger.
After the unexpected death of the Pope, Cardinal Lawrence is tasked with
managing the covert and ancient ritual of electing a new one.
Sequestered in the Vatican with the Catholic Church’s most powerful leaders until the process is
complete, Lawrence finds himself at the center of a conspiracy that could lead to its downfall.
Lawrence, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Bellini, played by Stanley Tucci.
Tremblay, played by John Lithgow.
Sister Agnes, played by Isabella Rossellini.
Adeyemi, played by Lucian Msamati.
Benitez, played by Carlos Diehz.
Conclave is a 2024 political thriller film directed by Edward Berger and written
by Peter Straughan, based on the 2016 novel by Robert Harris.
The film stars Ralph Fiennes, Stanley Tucci, John Lithgow,
Sergio Castellitto, and Isabella Rossellini.
In the film, Cardinal Thomas Lawrence (Fiennes) organizes a conclave to elect the next pope and
finds himself investigating secrets and scandals about the major candidates.
After premiering at the 51st Telluride Film Festival on 30 August 2024, Conclave was released in theaters in the United
States by Focus Features on 25 October 2024 and in the United Kingdom by Black Bear UK on 29 November 2024.
The film received positive reviews from critics, who praised the
performances, directing, screenplay, and cinematography.
The film has grossed $128 million worldwide on a $20 million production budget.
The film experienced a resurgence in popularity following the death of Pope Francis in April 2025 and the
subsequent conclave in May that resulted in the election of Pope Leo XIV, who reportedly saw the film.
Conclave was named one of the top ten films of 2024 by the National
Board of Review and the American Film Institute.
Among other accolades, it won four awards at the 78th British Academy Film Awards (tying The Brutalist for most of the ceremony), including Best Film, and
also won the Golden Globe Award for Best Screenplay and the Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Cast in a Motion Picture.
At the 97th Academy Awards, it received eight nominations,
including Best Picture, and won Best Adapted Screenplay.
The film explores themes of vatican (holy see), pope,
religion, election, roman catholic church.
The tone is emotional and intense.